<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Feldmann</title>
    <description>Chris Feldmann is an Interaction / Visual / Motion Designer</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:05:37 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 00:05:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Derby Hatterizer</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://interactives.courier-journal.com/projects/derby-hatterizer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the live project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;div class = &quot;portfolio-desc&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Concept Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Derby Hatterizer is a web app that maximizes the fashion frenzy in Louisville surrounding the Kentucky Derby. It allows users to take/upload their photos and digitally place a Kentucky Derby hat on their heads, or even design their own. The user can then share their final image on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stakeholders at the Courier-Journal wanted to provide a unique Kentucky Derby-themed digital experience for the online subscribers. The goal was to generate social engagement by having users participate in using a digital product and sharing the result on social media.  We would measure success of the project based on unique visitors to the interactive project as well as generated social engagement (Facebook shares) from our younger (Millennial) online subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Brainstorm&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I co-lead brainstorming sessions with stakeholders to come up with ideas about what sort of product we could deliver. The initial thought was that we could create a simple website that allowed the users to decorate cartoon-stylized horses. I quickly created a mockup of such a product but after some initial user testing (based on opinion of the concept alone), the result wasn’t as engaging as we initially thought. Polled potential users couldn’t see themselves spending time decorating a cartoon horse and sharing the images with their friends. Back to the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I then had the thought that, perhaps, if the interactive was a bit more user-centric, we could increase engagement and promote social interaction. Perhaps, instead of designing and decorating horses, the user could upload a photo of themselves and design their own Kentucky Derby hat? We discussed the idea in another brainstorming session and the idea ended up running parallel to an idea of one of the primary stakeholders - and thus the Derby Hatterizer was born.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Sketch&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming out of the brainstorm sessions we knew we wanted to have a mobile and desktop experience, so I created a series of sketches to get a feel for the layout and overall UX of the interactive. I created the sketches before any competitive analysis because initially I did not want to be influenced by a similar product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Competitive Analysis&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did a little bit of digging to see if anyone else had produced a similar product. I did this to see if there would be any overlap in the product that we were creating. I also wanted to see what is successful about similar projects and to see if I could learn from any pitfalls in the competitor’s project. In this case the Indy Star had previously produced a similar interactive featuring the Indiana Colt’s quarterback’s neck-beard, or, “Neard&quot;. Screen capture below:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/hatterizer_neard.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;IndyStar Neard Interactive&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;From this analysis I was able to see that once the user went through the process of uploading their photo and placing the beard on their face, in order to share their photo they were required to download the image to their local drive and the manually upload to Facebook. This was simply too bulky and added too many stress points on the user. I knew going forward in the design of our interactive the process of taking/uploading the image and sharing to social media had to be more streamlined.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Lo-Fi Wireframes/Task Flow&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this phase my goal was to define basic UI layouts and the red routes of the user. Due to time constraints and input from stakeholders we decided to create the desktop version first and circle back to the mobile version after the desktop launch.&lt;h4&gt;Hi-Fi Mock up&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I created high-fidelity mockups at several key interaction points. Our developer then started coding the interactive based on our discussions of usability, the low fidelity wireframes and these higher fidelity mockups. I would have preferred that we create lower fidelity prototypes and completed task analysis usability testing, however, time constraints did not allow it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/hatterizer_hi-fi_01.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;Hatterizer Hi-Fi 01&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/hatterizer_hi-fi_02.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;Hatterizer Hi-Fi 02&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/hatterizer_hi-fi_03.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;Hatterizer Hi-Fi 03&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/hatterizer_hi-fi_04.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;Hatterizer Hi-Fi 04&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I also created a high fidelity interactive mockup using inVision so the Courier-Journal advertising department could show potential sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://invis.io/HB33BJ6UY&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; See the interactive mockup.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Usability Testing&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the high fidelity prototype was completed (basically a Beta version of the project), I was then able to complete a few unmoderated usability tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Revisions and Launch&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I presented the stakeholders with some of the findings from the usability testing and proposed alterations to the digital product. I then took the key insights from the usability testing and implemented some changes within the product. Notably I clarified some of the iconography and made a few adjustments to how the user manipulated the hat objects. Once the major revisions were made to stakeholders’ acceptance we launched the product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to time constraints and other projects that we wanted to launch for the Kentucky Derby coverage, the stakeholders opted to forego the mobile version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The product received over 1500 unique views to the page. There were numerous submissions to the CJ curated gallery, and many Facebook shares. Overall a successful project; however, I regret not pushing the for a mobile-first development of this project. Many users approached me about the product and mentioned that they were trying to use the product from their phone and mentioned difficulties using the interactive from their mobile device. Going forward I will both be thinking of, and encouraging a mobile-first implementation on our digital products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction%20design/2014/07/18/derby-hatterizer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction%20design/2014/07/18/derby-hatterizer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>visual/interaction design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cj Grad Selfie Mobile</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://interactives.courier-journal.com/cjgrad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See what we launched!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;div class = &quot;portfolio-desc&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Concept Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CJ Grad Selfie project is a user generated content mobile-first photo gallery that pulls in user’s photos from Instagram that use &amp;#35;CJgradSelfie. A user is then randomly selected to win a weekend pass to Forecastle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Courier-Journal wanted a way to increase awareness of their Instagram account and encourage people to follow the Courier-Journal Instagram account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Brainstorm&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I co-lead brainstorming sessions with stakeholders to discuss what sort of digital product would best meet their business challenge. We discussed options for scraping both Twitter and Instragram photos that use the &amp;#35;CJgradSelfie, but ultimately it was decided that they wanted to focus solely on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Sketch&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming out of the brainstorm sessions I knew that since we were focusing primarily on Instagram photos, this experience should be mobile-first. This is because while Twitter has an ability to upload content from both mobile and desktop platforms, Instagram (without using special tools as a work-around) is primarily a mobile product.&lt;h4&gt;Lo-Fi Wireframes/Task Flow&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this phase my goal was to define basic UI layouts and the red routes of the user. Due to time constraints and input from stakeholders we decided to create the desktop version first and circle back to the mobile version after the desktop launch.&lt;h4&gt;Hi-Fi Mock up&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I created high-fidelity mockups at several key interaction points. For this project, I even created an animation that displayed the animation elements and transitions that the user would encounter during use of the product. Our developer then started coding the interactive based on our discussions of usability, the low fidelity wireframes and these higher fidelity mockups. I would have preferred that we create lower fidelity prototypes and completed task analysis usability testing, however, time constraints did not allow it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/cjgrad_hi-fi_01.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;CJgrad Hi-Fi 01&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/cjgrad_hi-fi_02.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;CJgrad Hi-Fi 02&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/portfolio/cjgrad_hi-fi_03.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; alt&quot;CJgrad Hi-Fi 03&quot;&gt;&lt;video src= &quot;../img/portfolio/CJgrad_mobileDesign.m4v&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-centered&quot; controls poster=&quot;../img/portfolio/cjgrad_hi-fi_01.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We launched a beta version of the site in order to get the ball rolling before the majority of schools in the area have their graduation ceremonies. The plan is to implement some of the finer designer elements (animation, designed transitions, etc.) once, and if, this project picks up momentum. If the stakeholders decide to continue development of the project I will perform usability testing. This order of the design process is not ideal. I would prefer to create rapid low-fidelity prototypes of the product and let user feedback inform design decisions, but we do what time/budget allows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re still rolling out and promoting the project. I will update this section once we have some viable results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction/motion%20design/2014/07/17/CJ-grad-Selfie-Mobile/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction/motion%20design/2014/07/17/CJ-grad-Selfie-Mobile/</guid>
        
        
        <category>visual/interaction/motion design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Derby360</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.courier-journal.com/pages/interactives/derby360/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;See the live project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/br&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction%20design,%20project%20management,%20video%20editing/2014/07/16/Derby360/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/visual/interaction%20design,%20project%20management,%20video%20editing/2014/07/16/Derby360/</guid>
        
        
        <category>visual/interaction design, project management, video editing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keto Calculator</title>
        <description>&lt;div class = &quot;portfolio-desc&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Concept Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The user is a parent with a child diagnosed with epilepsy who wants assistance in administering the ketogenic diet for seizure control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/interaction/motion%20design/2014/07/15/keto-calculator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/interaction/motion%20design/2014/07/15/keto-calculator/</guid>
        
        
        <category>interaction/motion design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graphic Examples</title>
        <description>Use this area of the page to describe your project. The icon above is part of a free icon set by &lt;a href=&quot;https://sellfy.com/p/8Q9P/jV3VZ/&quot;&gt;Flat Icons&lt;/a&gt;. On their website, you can download their free set with 16 icons, or you can purchase the entire set with 146 icons for only $12!</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/web%20development/2014/07/15/graphic-examples/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/web%20development/2014/07/15/graphic-examples/</guid>
        
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Motion Reel</title>
        <description>Use this area of the page to describe your project. The icon above is part of a free icon set by &lt;a href=&quot;https://sellfy.com/p/8Q9P/jV3VZ/&quot;&gt;Flat Icons&lt;/a&gt;. On their website, you can download their free set with 16 icons, or you can purchase the entire set with 146 icons for only $12!</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/web%20development/2014/07/14/motion-reel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/web%20development/2014/07/14/motion-reel/</guid>
        
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
